<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on KS Blog</title>
    <link>https://callmeks.github.io/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on KS Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.3</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 16:07:05 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://callmeks.github.io/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Journey of Cybersec</title>
      <link>https://callmeks.github.io/posts/my-journey-of-cybersec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:54:52 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://callmeks.github.io/posts/my-journey-of-cybersec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-about-myself&#34;&gt;Introduction about myself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a student that complated university studies related to cybersecurity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a CTF player&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learnt cybersecurity for a few years but still weak in it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-i-learn-ethical-hacking&#34;&gt;How I learn ethical hacking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-0&#34;&gt;Part 0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know about red team and blue team and I just decided to learn hacking for fun. Since hacking others looks more fun, I decided to look into videos and anything related. The first courses I go through is actually Practical Ethical Hacking from TCM Security. After going through the first few topic of the course, I have some basic understanding about how hacking works (that&amp;rsquo;s what I thought back then). Eventually, I stopped the course halfway because the course started to go through hackthebox retired machine and I don&amp;rsquo;t have a VIP account to follow along. Instead, I decided to move on with PicoCTF and Tryhackme as some of the people mentioned this 2 platform is great for learning cybersecurity. I further improved my basic skills such as linux command and getting more new knowledge from Tryhackme since it has a lot of different room. As for PicoCTF, I was stunned for quite some times as that is the first time I find out about CTF. That is also when I found out that there are a lot of different hacking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journey of Creating Android CTF</title>
      <link>https://callmeks.github.io/posts/journey-of-creating-android-ctf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 16:07:05 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://callmeks.github.io/posts/journey-of-creating-android-ctf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview-about-the-journey&#34;&gt;Overview about the journey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have 0 knowledge about kotlin as well as creating Android APK. Most of the things that I mentioned below is also my first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-0&#34;&gt;PART 0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the part where I started out by exploring how to create an Android APK. Basically just tons of youtube vidoes and blogs. The final decision? I just go with Android Studio. The installation is simple but remember to download system image for Virtual Device which is also a part of Android Studio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
